Michelangelo,
born
in
1475,
was a
sculptor,
painter, and
architect
who
transformed the
face of
Renaissance art.
His
statue
of
David created
when he
was
just
in
his 20s
is a
masterpiece of
Renaissance sculpture.
The Sistine
Chapel ceiling,
painted
by Michelangelo,
features the
famous
scene of
the creation
of
Adam.
Michelangelo's
work
on
the
Medici
Chapel
influences renowned
for its
architectural
innovation
and
sculptural
figures.
His
later
work,
The Last
Judgment,
is a
powerful fresco
that covers
the entire
alter wall
of the
Sistine Chapel.
Michelangelo's
artistic influence
extended
beyond his
works,
inspiring generations
of artists
and shaping
the
course
of Western
art.
Like, share,
and
subscribe
for more
inspiring
stories
of
our history's
greatest
masters.